{"tossups": [{"question": "A letter by Leonel Sharp provides this work\u2019s most widely accepted text, including the promises\u201cyou have deserved rewards and crowns\u201d and \u201cwe shall shortly have a famous victory.\u201d In this speech, the speaker thinks \u201cfoul scorn that Parma or Spain [...] should dare to invade the borders of my realm\u201dbefore promising to take up arms, despite having a \u201cweak, feeble\u201d body. For the point, name this 1588 speech delivered to an army awaiting the landing of the Spanish Armada by a leader who had the \u201cheart and stomach of a King,\u201d Elizabeth I.", "answer": "<b> Tilbury</b> Speech (accept descriptions that use the name<b> Tilbury</b>; prompt on descriptions that don\u2019t, such as \u201cQueen Elizabeth\u2019s speech to her army about the incoming Spanish Armada\u201d or portions thereof, so long as the player includes something that the tossup hasn\u2019t gotten to yet)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This man represented holders of the Wentworth Grants in a New York court case; protecting his interests in those grants led this man and his family to form the Onion River Company. Late in life, this man published the deist book<em> Reason: The Only Oracle of Man</em>. After a meeting at Catamount Tavern, this man organized a militia group that went on to aid Benedict Arnold in the capture of Fort Ticonderoga. For the point, name this man who advocated independence for Vermont and who led the Green Mountain Boys.", "answer": "Ethan<b> Allen</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "During a siege of this city, its defenders set fire to ramps trying to scale the Antonia Fortress. This city was refounded as Aelia Capitolina by Hadrian and kept that name for six centuries. The historian Josephus defected and recorded the siege of this city, which came after an attack on the Mount of Olives by forces that included the Zealots. Factions led by Simon ben Giora and John of Giscala split this city, which was captured by the future emperor Titus. For the point, name this city that was sacked by the Romans in 70 AD, leading to the destruction of the Second Temple.", "answer": "<b> Jerusalem</b>", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "This man\u2019s participation as an Arizona poll watcher in Operation Eagle Eye, a Republican minority vote-disruption campaign, was challenged by the Senate during his confirmation hearings. This graduate of Stanford Law School dated Sandra Day O\u2019Connor during his time there. This Chief Justice\u2019s opinion in <em>US v. Morrison</em> limited the power of the Violence Against Women Act of 1994. For the point, name this man who was succeeded by John Roberts as Chief Justice after his 2005 death.", "answer": "William<b> Rehnquist</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "This figure \u201cteaches the higher fidelity that negates the gods\u201d and concludes, like Oedipus, \u201cthat all is well\u201d according to a work that later notes \u201cthe struggle itself toward the heights is enough to fill a man\u2019s heart.\u201d This figure is the subject of an essay which ends by noting that \u201cone must imagine [this figure] happy.\u201d For the point, name this mythological figure, the subject of a landmark 1942 existentialist essay by Albert Camus [ca-moo] that discusses the story of this man forever pushing a boulder up a mountain.", "answer": "<b> Sisyphus</b> (accept The Myth of<b> Sisyphus</b>)", "metadata": "Literature - European Literature - Misc Literature"}, {}, {"question": "This figure formed the League of the Rhine to check Austrian expansion. This figure was exiled to Germany after attempting to arrest the Grand Cond\u00b4e, Louis de Bourbon, but returned with the help of the marshal Turenne. In his early years, this man assumed a co-regency with Anne of Austria. Though he secured peace with Spain in the Treaty of the Pyrenees, this man\u2019s tax policies led to the Fronde revolt. For the point, name this man who advised Louis XIV of France and succeeded the duke of Richelieu as cardinal.", "answer": "Cardinal Jules Raymond<b> Mazarin</b> (or Giulio Raimondo<b> Mazzarin</b>o)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This war began with the imposition of a ten cent tax, and Lynch\u2019s expedition was sent during this war to collect other taxes. During this war, the<em> Cochrane</em> and the<em> Blanco Encalada</em> defeated the ironclad <em>Hu\u00b4ascar</em> in the Battle of Angamos. One nation lost Tarapac\u00b4a and allowed the victor of this war to occupy Tacna and Arica, while another gave up the province of Antofagasta and its access to the sea. Control of saltpeter mines in the Atacama Desert was the impetus of, for the point, what 1879-1883 war in which Chile defeated Peru and Bolivia, named after a nearby ocean?", "answer": "War of the<b> Pacific</b> (or Guerra del<b> Pacifico</b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "During this man\u2019s presidency, Secretary of the Treasury Oliver Wolcott was forced to resign when he was accused of trying to burn down the State Department. This president turned many German-Americans against his party when he ordered the suppression of Fries\u2019s Rebellion. Residency requirements for obtaining citizenship were increased to fourteen years by this man\u2019s government via the Alien and Sedition Acts. For the point, name this second president of the U.S.", "answer": "<b> J</b>ohn<b> Adams</b> (prompt on Adams; do not accept John Quincy Adams)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "A character decides to take up this profession after he is framed in an assassination plot and sentenced to face tattooing and permanent exile. The so-called \u201cOriginal Seven\u201d people with this profession deprive a corrupt imperial tutor of the gifts from his birthday procession. A novel sometimes titled after a group of people with this profession opens with a description of 108 spirits being released from a turtle shell. For the point, name this profession, the subject of the Chinese novel<em> Water Margin</em>, which is often alternatively titled for these people<em> of the Marsh</em>.", "answer": "<b> outlaw</b>s (or<em><b> Outlaw</b>s of the Marsh</em>; or equivalents such as<b> thieves</b> or<b> bandit</b>s)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Misc Arts"}, {"question": "This city is connected to its suburb of Longueil by the Jacques Cartier Bridge. It was the site of a 1989 agreement that phased out HFCs and CFCs in order to protect the ozone layer, this city\u2019s namesake \u201cprotocol.\u201d For the point, name this French and English-speaking city on an island in the St. Lawrence River, the most populous city in Quebec.", "answer": "<b> Montreal</b> Page 3", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {"question": "At this battle, Cynaegirus had his hand cut off while trying to reel in an enemy ship. It is unknown whether Themistocles served as a<em> strategos</em> at this battle or simply fought in it; in the aftermath of this battle, Themistocles advocated the revamping of the Athenian fleet to protect against an invasion that came ten years later. Miltiades led the Athenians at, for the point, what victory over the Persians that ended Darius\u2019 invasion of Greece in 490 BC?", "answer": "Battle of<b> Marathon</b>", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {"question": "In one essay, this man proposed a four-hour workday in order to reduce unemployment and increase leisure time among the masses. This philosopher attacked the modern institution of marriage as \u201cbehind the times\u201d since the advent of contraception. This author of<em> Marriage and Morals</em> and<em> In Praise of</em> <em>Idleness</em> hypothesized an imaginary, floating teapot in a thought experiment meant to shift the burden of proof in debates on the existence of God. With Alfred North Whitehead, this man wrote a definitive three-volume work on the foundations of math. For the point, name this British philosopher and co-author of a 20th century<em> Principia Mathematica</em>.", "answer": "Bertrand (Arthur William)<b> Russell</b>", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {}, {"question": "<em>The Independent</em> responded to this event with an image of a hand coming out of a page giving the middle finger and holding a pen dripping blood. This event had supposedly been triggered by a picture with the caption \u201clove is stronger than hate\u201d written above a man kissing the Prophet Muhammad. The week after this event, the target responded with the words \u201call is forgiven\u201d written above a cartoon of Muhammad holding a sign declaring \u201cJe suis Charlie.\u201d [zhe swee shar-lee] For the point, name this January 2015 attack on a French satirical magazine.", "answer": "<b> Charlie Hebdo</b> massacre (or equivalents) Page 4", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {}, {}, {"question": "This event was nearly derailed until the creation of a namesake part of Poland and the Province of Saxony. Spain was the lone member of the \u201cBig Eight\u201d to not agree to the result of this event. The Holy Alliance was created by Tsar Alexander I to preserve the effects of this event, whose Final Act created borders that stayed largely the same for 40 years. Talleyrand was able to negotiate a strong place for France at this event, which was dominated by Klemens von Metternich. For the point, name this event that shaped Europe after the fall of Napoleon.", "answer": "<b> Congress of Vienna</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "Willard Bay was separated from this body of water to create a reservoir in 1964. Gunnison Bay is separated from the rest of this body of water by the Lucin Cutoff, a railroad causeway that was built to replace a route that curved north of this lake. This lake is descended from the prehistoric Lake Bonneville, and it lies south of Promontory Summit, where the Golden Spike completed the first transcontinental railroad. A Brigham Young-led party of Mormon pioneers settled a valley named for, for the point, what large, saline body of water in Utah?", "answer": "<b> Great Salt Lake</b>", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {"question": "Nathaniel Ward compiled the first legal code of this colony in the \u201cBody of Liberties.\u201d This colony executed Mary Dyer due to a law banning the presence of Quakers. Shortly after the<em> Arbella</em> arrived at this colony, its founder gave the \u201cModel of Christian Charity\u201d speech to urge the community to act as a\u201ccity upon a hill.\u201d Rhode Island was founded when Roger Williams and Anne Hutchinson were expelled from this colony. John Winthrop founded, for the point, what New England colony that contained the city of Boston?", "answer": "<b> Massachusetts Bay</b> Colony (prompt on Massachusetts alone) Page 5", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This man\u2019s most notable campaign is said to have coined the phrase \u201clet\u2019s look at the record.\u201d This governor blasted William Randolph Hearst as \u201ca man as low and mean as I can picture.\u201d This man was the\u201cwet\u201d candidate at the convention that was split between him and William McAdoo. He eventually turned against his prot\u00b4eg\u00b4e and successor as governor, Franklin Roosevelt. This man\u2019s opposition to Prohibition and his Catholicism hurt his presidential aspirations. For the point, name this New York Governor who lost to Herbert Hoover in the 1928 election.", "answer": "Alfred \u201cAl\u201d<b> Smith</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "A nurse with broken glasses in one of these artworks inspired paintings by Francis Bacon. A German Expressionist work in this medium centers on a murderous hypnotist. One part of a work in this medium shows a baby in a stroller rolling down the Odessa Steps and was created by Sergei Eisenstein. This artistic medium was used to create<em> The Cabinet of Dr. Caligari</em> and<em> The Battleship Potemkin</em>. For the point, identify this artistic genre that became known as \u201ctalkies\u201d with the addition of sound and, with <em>The Wizard of Oz</em>, included color.", "answer": "(silent)<b> film</b>making (accept equivalents like<b> cinema</b>,<b> movie</b>s,<b> cinematography</b>, etc.; the first sentence discusses Battleship Potemkin, so accept answers relating to it (i.e. \u201cRussian films\u201d) until\u201cGerman\u201d is said)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Film"}, {"question": "The historic site of Bulow Plantation is found in this state, which was granted statehood at the same time as the non-slave state of Iowa as part of the terms of an 1845 compromise. A Native American reservation in this state was created by the Treaty of Moultrie Creek. Billy Bowlegs and Osceola [oss-ee-oh-lah] led a Native American tribe in this state that fought a series of three wars against the U.S. in the 19th century. For the point, name this home state of the Seminoles.", "answer": "<b> Florida</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "A civil war in this state known as the Great Feudal War targeted Vasily II. This state was allowed to capture Vladimir after an alliance made between its ruler Yuri and Uzbek Khan. Its capital was sacked by Tokhtamysh after its leader, Dmitry Donskoy, led a coalition to defeat the Golden Horde at the Battle of Kulikovo. This state conquered Novgorod under Ivan the Great and plunged into the Time of Troubles after the death of Ivan the Terrible. For the point, name this precursor to the Russian state, centered at the modern capital.", "answer": "Grand Duchy of<b> Moscow</b> (or<b> Muscovy</b>; do not accept or prompt on Russia)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "One member of this family noted that \u201ceach time a man [...] strikes out against injustice, he sends out a ripple of hope\u201d in the Day of Affirmation speech. Another member of this family asserted that the\u201cthe dream will never die\u201d after conceding to Jimmy Carter at the 1980 Democratic National Convention, the third time a member of this family ran for President. For the point, name this family whose only U.S. President declared \u201cask not what your country can do for you, ask what you can do for your country\u201d in his 1961 Inaugural Address.", "answer": "<b> Kennedy</b> family (accept Robert, Edward \u201cTed,\u201d and/or John<b> Kennedy</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "This event culminated in a conversation at the Sidrat al-Muntaha, a \u201cLote-tree beyond which none may pass.\u201d The steed Buraq aided in this event, which involves visits to all seven<em> samaawat</em>. The 17th surah of the Quran, al-Isra, opens by briefly describing this event, which began at the Masjid al-Haram. During this event, the command for Muslims to pray 50 times per day was reduced to five on Moses\u2019advice during a conversation with Allah. For the point, name this 621 spiritual event in which Muhammad traveled to the \u201cfarthest mosque,\u201d then ascended to heaven.", "answer": "Muhammad\u2019s<b> Night Journey</b> (accept<b> Isra and Mi\u2019raj</b> before Isra is mentioned, prompting if either half is given alone; prompt on descriptive answers regarding Muhammad ascending to and/or visiting heaven)", "metadata": "Religion - Religion"}, {"question": "This man ordered Operation Flowers Are Blooming to intervene in the Seychelles. This man\u2019s government passed a law reversing the Shah Bono decision. This man and Ottavio Quattrocchi came under suspicion in the Bofors scandal. He claimed that \u201cwhen a mighty tree falls, it is only natural that the earth around it does shake a little\u201d to explain violent riots when he took office. The Path of Light traces the steps of this man before he was assassinated in 1991 by a Tamil Tiger. For the point, name this Indian prime minister, the husband of Sonia and son of Indira.", "answer": "<b> R</b>ajiv<b> Gandhi</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "This man asked \u201cIs your money that good? Will it buy you forgiveness? Do you think that it could?\u201din a work condemning the \u201cMasters of War.\u201d He noted that \u201cThe cavalries charged/the Indians died\u201d in a work that lists American military actions and notes \u201cyou don\u2019t count the dead when God\u2019s on your side.\u201dThis singer rhetorically asked \u201cHow many roads must a man walk down?\u201d in \u201cBlowin\u2019 in the Wind,\u201d and advised people to \u201cadmit that the waters around you have grown\u201d in \u201cThe Times They Are A-Changin.\u201dFor the point, name this American protest singer and 2016 Nobel Laureate.", "answer": "Bob<b> Dylan</b> (or Robert<b> Zimmerman</b>)", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Poetry"}, {"question": "The first assault in this battle was met by the company of Joseph Bartholomew. The losing side of this battle interpreted the subsequent New Madrid Earthquakes as an omen to renew their war effort. During this battle, Spier Spencer led a militia group called the Yellow Jackets. One side in this battle was led by Tenskwatawa from Prophetstown, while the leader of the winning side capitalized on success at this battle with a campaign song. For the point, name this 1811 battle in Tecumseh\u2019s War, won by future President William Henry Harrison.", "answer": "Battle of<b> Tippecanoe</b> Page 8", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "One member of this family collaborated with Malcolm X\u2019s daughter, Attallah Shabazz, to produce the play<em> Stepping into Tomorrow</em>. The matriarch of this family was the target of a smear campaign by the FBI, who mailed her tapes of her husband\u2019s alleged affairs; that woman led a march of sanitation workers on April 8, 1968, less than a week after the murder of her husband. For the point, identify this family, including Yolanda, her mother Coretta Scott, and Coretta Scott\u2019s husband, a prominent civil rights activist.", "answer": "<b> King</b> (accept Yolanda<b> King</b>; accept Coretta Scott<b> King</b>; accept Martin Luther<b> King</b>, Jr.)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "A poem about a man who died during this activity repeats the lines \u201cI will not see it!\u201d and \u201cAt five in the afternoon.\u201d People who engage in this activity are the subject of the book<em> Death in the Afternoon</em>. Lady Brett Ashley seduces a professional at this activity, Pedro Romero, in<em> The Sun Also Rises</em>. Members of the Generation of \u201898 began a movement opposing this activity, arguing that it was culturally backward and inhumane. Matadors engage in, for the point, what Spanish sport that is enjoyed after Pamplona\u2019s Running of the Bulls?", "answer": "<b> bullfight</b>ing (accept word forms)", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Misc Literature"}, {"question": "The press\u2019s role in this scandal was lambasted by the political cartoon \u201cEvery Public Question With An Eye Only To The Public Good.\u201d This scandal was exposed when a set of incriminating letters were published by the<em> New York Sun</em>, which wanted to hinder a re-election campaign. A company led by Oakes Ames was at the center of this scandal, and officials implicated in it included the sitting Vice President, Schuyler Colfax. For the point, name this scandal in which a holding company financing the Union Pacific Railroad bribed Congressmen.", "answer": "<b> Credit Mobilier</b> scandal Page 9", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "One side\u2019s plan for this battle was discovered by Rudolf Roessler, the head of the Lucy spy ring in Switzerland. Walther Model and Erich von Manstein were supposed to form a pincer around a salient in this battle, which was codenamed Operation Citadel by the Germans and constantly postponed so that more Panthers could reach the front, giving the Voronezh Front time to dig in at Prokhorovka. For the point, name this 1943 battle of the Eastern Front, the site of the largest tank engagement in history.", "answer": "Battle of<b> Kursk</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "For the point, name this socialist president of Chile whom the CIA replaced with Augusto Pinochet.", "answer": "Salvador<b> Allende</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "The Gamow Window refers to the set of conditions under which this process can occur due to quantum tunneling overcoming the Coulomb barrier. Hans Bethe worked out the steps of one form of this process, and the CNO cycle drives the conversion of hydrogen to helium via this process in stars. Martin Fleischmann and Stanley Pons falsely claimed to have generated a \u201ccold\u201d version of, for the point, what process in which two or more atomic nuclei combine to form one heavier atom, contrasted with nuclear fission?", "answer": "nuclear<b> fusion</b>", "metadata": "Science - Physics"}, {"question": "In this region, the Feast of the Pheasant was held to drum up support for a campaign against the Ottomans. A king of this region constructed the massive Mons Meg cannon as a gift for James II. The Treaty of Picquigny isolated this region from its English allies, who had earlier captured Joan of Arc with the help of this region\u2019s Philip the Good. The power of this region was eroded when Charles the Bold was killed at Nancy, allowing Louis XI to claim its lands. For the point, name this duchy of eastern France, famous for producing a dark red wine.", "answer": "Duchy of<b> Burgundy</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This man quipped \u201cFate doesn\u2019t want me to be famous too young\u201d when the Pulitzer committee did not award anyone in 1965. He included the spiritual \u201cCome Sunday\u201d in a three-part composition about the history of the Negro in America,<em> Black, Brown, and Beige</em>. This bandleader\u2019s signature song, written by his frequent collaborator Billy Strayhorn, was named for the subway train that went to Harlem. The house band at the Cotton Club was, for the point, what jazz pianist who wrote \u201cMood Indigo\u201d and performed \u201cTake the A Train\u201d?", "answer": "Edward Kennedy \u201cDuke\u201d<b> Ellington</b> Page 10", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Jazz"}, {"question": "A neighborhood of this city experienced so much racially motivated violence that it was nicknamed Dynamite Hill. The Cahaba boys set off a bomb, in the midst of a civil rights campaign against Bull Connor\u2019s brutal police tactics, near this city\u2019s 16th Street Baptist Church. A text produced in this city declared \u201cInjustice anywhere is a threat to justice everywhere.\u201d For the point, name this Alabama city where an imprisoned Martin Luther King, Jr. wrote a famous letter defending nonviolence.", "answer": "<b> Birmingham</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This leader oversaw the establishment of the \u201chousehold responsibility system,\u201d which helped lead to the rise of \u201cten thousand yuan households.\u201d Under this leader, the phrase \u201cseek truth from facts\u201dwas promulgated as part of a process that established four Special Economic Zones. The phrase \u201cto get rich is glorious\u201d was also promoted during the tenure of this politician, who suggested \u201cIt doesn\u2019t matter whether a cat is white or black, as long as it catches mice.\u201d For the point, name this leader who presided over the beginning of China\u2019s market reforms in the 1980s.", "answer": "<b> Deng</b> Xiaoping", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "During these conflicts, the Walcheren Campaign failed due to disease among British troops, and an Irish uprising was defeated at the Battle of Ballinamuck. The hardship caused by these conflicts led to the passage of the Corn Laws. Lord Grenville created the Ministry of All the Talents to oversee these conflicts after the death of William Pitt the Younger. Britain was targeted by the Continental System during these conflicts and threatened by the<em> Grande Arm\u00b4ee</em>. For the point, name this series of conflicts that ended with a British-led coalition defeating the namesake French emperor at Waterloo.", "answer": "<b> Napoleonic</b> Wars (or the<b> Coalition</b> Wars)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "A century-old argument made in this case by Attorney General William Wirt was finally settled by 1964\u2019s<em> Sears v. Stiffel</em>, which questioned whether patent law was sufficient to resolve its question. Daniel Webster argued for the winning side in this case, which included \u201cnavigation\u201d as part of Congress\u2019s powers under the Commerce Clause. A steamboat license granted to Robert Fulton in New York was challenged in this case, whose majority opinion was written by John Marshall. For the point, name this 1824 case which expanded Congress\u2019s power to regulate interstate commerce.", "answer": "<b> Gibbons</b> v.<b> Ogden</b> (accept either, and accept both in either order)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "At the end of his career, this artist sculpted a ragged and emaciated Mary Magdalene from wood. He included a decapitated head at the base of a statue for the Medici Palace; that work shows the subject in a<em> contrapposto</em> pose with a flowered hat, and is considered to be the first freestanding nude since antiquity. This artist\u2019s statue of Erasmo di Narni drew heavily on an equestrian statue of Marcus Aurelius. For the point, name this Italian sculptor of<em> Gattamelata</em> and a bronze<em> David</em>.", "answer": "<b> Donatello</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {"question": "In 2000 several European Union countries imposed sanctions on this country after the \u00a8OVP entered a coalition government with Jorg Haider\u2019s political party. A 2016 presidential election in this country was redone because 77,000 absentee votes were counted too early. In that election, Green candidate Alexander Van der Bellen eventually defeated far-right FP\u00a8O candidate Norbert Hofer. For the point, name this country, led until 2016 by Heinz Fischer from Vienna.", "answer": "<b> Austria</b> (or<b>\u00a8Osterreich</b>)", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "In what is now this country, Sri Indraditya founded the Phra Ruang dynasty, later led by King Ram Khamhaeng, who created a modern alphabet. In the 17th century, Narai ruled another kingdom in this modern country, accepting French diplomats and missionaries like Guy Tachard. European powers never colonized this Asian country, which was once ruled by Mongkut. For the point, name this modern-day country where the Sukhothai and Ayutthaya [ah-yoo-tah-yah] kingdoms once ruled in what the Europeans called Siam.", "answer": "Kingdom of<b> Thailand</b> (accept<b> Siam</b> before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "This man appointed Henry Morgenthau, Sr. as ambassador to the Ottoman Empire as compensation for Morgenthau having managed the finances of his presidential campaign. During a political convention, this man outmaneuvered Champ Clark to earn the presidential nomination. This president signed the Underwood Tariff and established the Federal Reserve and Federal Trade Commission as part of his New Freedom program. For the point, name this president who led the U.S. into World War I in 1917.", "answer": "Woodrow<b> Wilson</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "A poem addressed to a woman of this name begins \u201cWhen you are very old\u201d and was written by Pierre de Ronsard. A woman with this name in an Edgar Allan Poe poem reminds the speaker of \u201cthe glory that was Greece, / And the grandeur that was Rome.\u201d When a shade of this name is conjured in the play<em> Doctor Faustus</em>, she is asked \u201cWas this the face that launch\u2019d a thousand ships?\u201d For the point, name the wife of Menelaus whose elopement with Paris sparked the Trojan War.", "answer": "<b> Helen</b> (accept<b> Helen</b> of Troy)", "metadata": "Literature - British Literature - Poetry"}, {"question": "This leader\u2019s party was split between supporters of Chancellor of the Exchequer Hugh Gaitskell and Health Secretary Aneurin Bevan. This leader nationalized the Big Four railway companies and created the National Coal Board. This leader\u2019s government sought to fight the \u201cFive Great Evils,\u201d as laid out in the Beveridge Report, by creating a cradle-to-grave welfare state, including the National Health Service. For the point, name this Labour prime minister who succeeded Winston Churchill after World War II.", "answer": "Clement<b> Attlee</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This man\u2019s treatment of the upper classes was satirized by the cartoonist Jos\u00b4e Guadalupe Posada. He chose to announce his retirement in<em> Pearson\u2019s Magazine</em> but was re-elected anyway. This man, who was advised by a group known as the Cient\u00b4\u0131ficos, came to power after issuing the Plan de Tuxtepec [toosh-teh-peck]; he also issued the failed Plan de la Noria after his loss to Benito Juarez in a presidential election. Francisco Madero overthrew, for the point, what longtime dictator who was deposed in the Mexican Revolution?", "answer": "Porfirio<b> D\u00b4\u0131az</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "After this man fled to Italy, \u00b4Eamon de Valera invited him to lead an Institute of Advanced Study in Dublin, Ireland. This scientist discussed the idea of an \u201caperiodic crystal\u201d that could carry genetic information and provide a link between physics, biology, and chemistry in his work<em> What is Life?</em>. This physicist\u2019s namesake equation can be used to study the time evolution of a system\u2019s wave function. For the point, name this Austrian physicist who developed a thought experiment involving radioactive decay, a vial of poison, and a helpless cat.", "answer": "Erwin<b> Schr\u00a8odinger</b> Page 13", "metadata": "Science - Physics"}, {"question": "One member of this family was the first to serve<em> after</em> the ratification of the Constitution as Governor of Virginia. Another member of this family served as the first Attorney General and opposed Alexander Hamilton\u2019s work on Jay\u2019s Treaty. A third member of this family served as the President of both the First and Second Continental Congresses before falling ill and being replaced with Henry Middleton and John Hancock, respectively. Beverley, Edmund, and Peyton were members of, for the point, what prominent Virginia political family?", "answer": "<b> Randolph</b> (accept Beverley, Edmund, and/or Peyton<b> Randolph</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "This composer researched English folk melodies for his opera<em> Henry VIII</em> and led a failed attempt to boycott German music during World War I. This composer used the xylophone to represent dancing skeletons multiple times, such as in the \u201cFossils\u201d section of a work that he refused to publish in full. This composer did allow the publication of a movement that uses the cello and piano to depict a bird floating on water. For the point, name this composer of the<em> Dance Macabre</em> who included \u201cThe Swan\u201d in his <em>Carnival of the Animals</em>.", "answer": "Camille<b> Saint-Saens</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {}, {"question": "<em>Note: Three answers required.</em> The Voice Dialogue method is a way of engaging one of these three things to bring it in harmony with the other two. James Strachey\u2019s translation of these concepts has been criticized by Bruno Bettelheim. One of these three concepts is weaker in women because they do not identify with the father as much as men do with their mothers; that concept was explored in a book titled for two of these concepts, written by their formulator. Instinct, realism, and morality are modeled by, for the point, what three psychological concepts that theoretically make up the mind according to Sigmund Freud?", "answer": "<b> id, ego, and superego</b> (must have all 3; any order is fine; prompt if fewer than 3 are given) Page 14", "metadata": "Social Science - Social Science - Psychology"}, {}, {"question": "In 2009, the Census Bereau and this organization stopped providing their services to ACORN after edited videos showed ACORN giving advice on how to run a human trafficking ring. Ted Cruz\u2019s campaign proposed replacing this organization with a series of postcards or a mobile app. Lois Lerner resigned as head of this organization\u2019s Exempt Organization Unit in 2013, after this organization was criticized for scrutinizing conservative political groups. For the point, name this American governmental organization that collects taxes.", "answer": "<b> I</b>nternal<b> R</b>evenue<b> S</b>ervice", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "These vehicles used weapons named for heaven, earth, black, and yellow and were equipped with a head that spewed smoke and fumes, resembling a<em> panokseon</em>. These vehicles were first deployed after their commander feigned retreat at the Battle of Sacheon during the Imjin War. It is debated if these vehicles had iron plating, but they definitely had spikes to prevent enemies from boarding them, inspiring their name. For the point, identify these Korean ships, known for their armored, animal-like roof.", "answer": "<b> turtle ships</b> (or<b> geobukseon</b> or<b> gwiseon</b>; prompt on descriptive answers like \u201cKorean ships\u201dbefore \u201cKorea\u201d is read)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "The Schechter letter details this state\u2019s failed invasion of Khazaria and ensuing invasion of the Byzantine Empire, which ended in a failed 941 siege of Constantinople. That siege was led by Igor I, who ruled this state for three decades. Vladimir the Great Christianized this state, which moved its capital from Novgorod under Oleg, its first Grand Prince. The Mongols defeated this Rurikid-led state in the 13th century. For the point, name this Slavic state that controlled land in modern Russia and which is named in part for their capital city in modern Ukraine.", "answer": "Kievan<b> Rus</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "James Holman was the first mayor of this city, which was founded at Allen\u2019s Landing. Its namesake Ship Channel was developed by dredging Buffalo Bayou after a nearby coastal city was hit by a Category 4 hurricane in 1900. This city\u2019s Clear Lake area is home to the Mission Control Center for NASA\u2019s manned missions once Cape Canaveral finishes Mission Control for launch. The Johnson Space Center is in, for the point, what city, named for the victor of the Battle of San Jacinto and located inland from Galveston Bay in Texas?", "answer": "<b> Houston</b> Page 15", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}], "bonuses": []}